<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>&#43;वेङ्कटाचार्यदीक्षितः on मीमांसायां विश्वासटिप्पन्यः</title>
    <link>file:///data/vishvastAloka/mImAMsA/karma-kANDam/12-adhyAyAH/granthAH/venkaTAchAryadIxitaH/</link>
    <description>Recent content in &#43;वेङ्कटाचार्यदीक्षितः on मीमांसायां विश्वासटिप्पन्यः</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <atom:link href="file:///data/vishvastAloka/mImAMsA/karma-kANDam/12-adhyAyAH/granthAH/venkaTAchAryadIxitaH/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>विधित्रयपरित्राणम्</title>
      <link>file:///data/vishvastAloka/mImAMsA/karma-kANDam/12-adhyAyAH/granthAH/venkaTAchAryadIxitaH/vidhitrayaparitrANam/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>file:///data/vishvastAloka/mImAMsA/karma-kANDam/12-adhyAyAH/granthAH/venkaTAchAryadIxitaH/vidhitrayaparitrANam/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;[[विधित्रयपरित्राणम्&#x9;Source: &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.ebharatisampat.in/read_chapter.php?bookid=ODEyMzA5ODUxNDE0MTUy&#34;&gt;EB&lt;/a&gt;]]&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;[&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;श्री वेङ्कटेश्वर स्वामी, श्री गणपति स्वामी, श्री सरस्वति देवि,&lt;br&gt;&#xA;?0?2श्रीवेङ्कटेश्वरप्राच्यग्रन्थावली सं. 44.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;सम्पादकः&amp;mdash;?0 श्री प. वें. रामानुजस्वामीए एम.ए.?0&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;श्रीवेङ्कटेश्वरप्राच्यपरिशोधनालयाध्यक्षः&lt;br&gt;&#xA;अरशाणिपालै वेङ्कटाध्वरीति प्रसिद्धैः&lt;br&gt;&#xA;?0 श्रीवेङ्कटाचार्यदीक्षितै?0:&lt;br&gt;&#xA;विरचितं&lt;br&gt;&#xA;?0विधित्रयपरित्राणम्&lt;br&gt;&#xA;?0 -&amp;gt;ooo&amp;lt;-&lt;br&gt;&#xA;?0 ?0श्री वेङ्कटेश्वरप्राच्यमहाविद्यालयन्यायमीमांसाध्यापकेन?0&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;न्यायमीमांसोभयशिरोमणिना&lt;br&gt;&#xA;?0शब्दवङ्गीशवंश्येन?0&lt;br&gt;&#xA;?0को. शठकोपाचार्येण?0&lt;br&gt;&#xA;परिशोध्य परिष्कृतम्&lt;br&gt;&#xA;?0 -&amp;gt;o&amp;lt;-&lt;br&gt;&#xA;?0 ?0श्रीतिरुमल-तिरुपति देवस्थानमुद्रणालये मुद्रितम्&lt;br&gt;&#xA;?0 तिरुपति&lt;br&gt;&#xA;?0 ?0 ?01954&lt;br&gt;&#xA;?0&#xA;INTRODUCTION&lt;br&gt;&#xA;I am glad to introduce to the public the present work of Vidhitrayaparitranam written by the famous Venkatadhvarin who was a versatile scholar and is reputed to have written more than one hundred works in different sciences, although a major number of them is lost to us and only about twenty are now extant. It is a critical review of the views expressed by Appaya Diksita in his Vidhirasayanam in which the latter criticised the views expressed by Kumarila Bhatta in his famous Tantravartikam on the commentary on Mimamsasutras by Sabarasvamin. Venkatadhvarin examined the views of Appaya Diksita and proved that his criticism of Kumarila&amp;rsquo;s views cannot hold water scholars like Khandadeva, Sankarbhatta, Narayanasastrin have likewise criticised the views of Appaya Diksita but the present author, being posterior to them, could write is a more comprehensive and unassailable manner than his predecessors.&lt;br&gt;&#xA;The present edition is based upon two manuscripts found in the Library of the Institute, one of which is complete while the other is incomplete, with loss of some leaves in the middle. The complete manuscripts is partly in Telugu and partly in Grantha characters. Two manuscripts of the work are found in the Adyar library and in the Government Oriental Manuscripts Library, Madras. The former is full of lacunae and the latter is incomplete, covering only a portion of the first chapter. Both these were of practically no use for the present edition. It is therefore practically based on the single manuscript found in the library of the Institute. This is a fairly correct&lt;br&gt;&#xA;manuscript but a few letters here and there are lost owing to the breaking of the ends of leaves. These have been made good by the Editor. The Editor has taken great pains to prepare the edition of the work and I think he has done his best to present an authentic edition of the work. He has added an historical and critical introduction to the work in which he tried to fix the place of our author among the critics of Appaya Diksita.&lt;br&gt;&#xA;The Editor Mr. K. Sathakopacharya was on the staff of the Institure as Library Pandit for several years and was subsequently appointed Lecturer in Mimamsa in the Oriental College. He is a double Siromani of the Madras University in the subjects of Nyaya and Mimamsa. By virtue of his qualifications and experience, he is eminently fitted to edit a work like this. It is left to the readers to judge how he has accomplished his task.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
